hi just a quick behind the scenes video
because quite a few people asked how I
did the microchip atmail April Fool's
video and quite a lot of people are
guess it of course it's pretty easy so
here it is um uh yes I did have
something plugged into the back which
you didn't see there's an extra USB
cable headed off to you guessed it a pit
kit 3 but no it's not connected to a
different board it is actually connected
to the micral here just like in my um
triple 5 timer video what you didn't see
are a few wires there there we go headed
out the back through my anti static mat
of course and over to T there it is
there's the culprit there's a real pck
kit 3 of course dead easy just like the
triple 5 timer but aha a lot of people
said how did I do the LED on there this
thing was um you know flicker did I
actually have modify the real firmware
in there nah of course not not going to
go to that amount of trouble buger that
same thing when you're on when you're on
a winner stick with it there we go we
got some wires going under there and
because that lead is driven by um a you
know essentially um open collector
output from the microcontroller there
just used a resistor on the back shorted
it out and the
wires come out front of the mat here so
what you didn't see is me operating this
behind the scenes while I was uh sinking
while I was using the mouse button with
uh one hand I was uh secretly just uh
joining a couple of wires there and
there's the LED going there because all
I'm doing is uh um shorting out that um
well pulling pulling that resistor low
it's connected to the 5V rail on one end
and you just pull it low with the series
resistor on the other end so you can't
harm the um AVR dragon at all and well
that's all there is to it and you may
have actually uh caught this in the
video slightly uh you may be wondering
uh well how can I wire just the pit 3 in
parallel with that micro and also have
the pins from here doing it well I I
don't know if there's a buffer on there
or not that could be disabled or
something like that so I didn't bother
doing that so what it is is you may have
noticed that uh in the video some of
these wires have a bit more wobble on
them well look they've just fallen out
there because they actually had the pins
removed from them so they weren't
actually making contact down on that
board pretty basic I wasn't actually
going to do an April Fool's video I had
actually um given up because I went on a
uh a um 7-Day um holiday just before and
uh yeah I was trying I wanted to do
something a bit more elaborate but I
just ran out of time to do it really so
but um yes I was actually just going to
completely forget about it for this year
which I maybe would have made next
year's one better but um anyway um I at
the last minute I decided oh yeah I'll
do something like this and well and I
put it together like within like the
hour of uploading uh the thing just in
time I did it I raced to the lab did it
just in time and it uh worked a treat
fooled a few people so there you go
catch you next time